DAVID KANANDA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

A passionate and highly motivated Software
Developer with solid experience developing and
deploying web applications. Possess strong technical
skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and libraries/
frameworks such as React and React Native, as well as
back-end technologies such as NodeJS and MongoDB.
Strong desire to create professional work in a
challenging environment.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

2017 - present

React Native Developer

 Developing native mobile applications for clients such as ONEm

Brand42

Feb 2017 - Nov 2017

Full Stack Web Developer

- Working to deadlines collaborating with designers to deliver award winning web applications for clients such as Alfa Systems, Bloodwise, Veraison Education and Brand42
- Front-end development using JavaScript, HTML and CSS/SASS including libraries such as jQuery
- Back-end development using NodeJS, MongoDB and MySQL

University of Greenwich

Oct 2012 - Jan 2017

Software Developer

- Developing single page training environments using HTML, CSS and JavaScript as well as libraries/frameworks such as Angular2, rxJS and React
- Developing back-end data driven applications using NodeJS, MongoDB and MySQL
- Containerise and deploy web servers using Docker
- Deploying and prototyping on cloud computing platforms e.g. Digital Ocean

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science degree in Computing

2012

University of Greenwich

First Class Honours

Mobile: +44 794 1441633

Email: davidkananda@gmail.com Website: https://dmkcode.com/ Github: https://github.com/dmkcode

Twitter: @DMKCode

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidkananda/

SE₂ London. United Kingdom

SKILLS

JavaScript	••••
HTML5	••••
CSS	••••
React Native	••••
React	• • • • •
NodeJS	• • • • •
MongoDB	• • • • •
MySQL	• • • • •
Docker	• • • • •
AWS	• • • • •

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

AWARDS

- the lead developer in developing the Alfa Systems
 Investors website which has won a W3 Award for 2017
- part of the front-end dev team for the Bloodwise charity website which also won a W3 Award for 2017
- implemented a containerised development environment strategy using Docker eliminating dependency conflicts on developer machines

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- "Real-time Decision Support in Online Training Environments". - http://www.laccei.org/LACCEl2015-SantoDomingo/RefereedPapers/RP192.pdf
- "Design of an Immersive Online Crisis Preparation Learning Environment" http://idl.iscram.org/files/lizbacon/2016/1407_LizBacon_e tal2016.pdf

OTHER

- implemented a containerised development environment strategy using Docker eliminating dependency conflicts on developer machines
- Successfully migrated desktop applications to web applications such as training environments while working for University of Greenwich
- At University of Greenwich, I implemented restful web services consumed by EU projects such as Pandora and POP-Alert